Chidiebere Oduikolo

DN33, Grimsby

Mobile: 07424677625, Email: chidieberecosmas@gmail.com Junior Web Developer

Personal Profile

An enthusiastic, dedicated, and high-performing individual with about 6 years of experience as a Radiographer for the NHS. I've grown to appreciate the vital role IT plays in healthcare. Working with modern imaging software and equipment, as well as PACS, RIS and other digital systems, has fuelled my interest in IT. I've learnt the value of teamwork, attention to detail, and adhering to stringent deadlines. My passion for IT and software development prompted me to participate in a 12-week IT and software development training program, where I am gaining fundamental understanding of software and web development. The program offers technical training as well as hands-on project work to demonstrate my newly learnt skills. My goal is to improve and broaden my present skill set so that I can pursue a successful career in software development.

I have a strong background in programming languages such as Python and JavaScript, as well as familiarity with web development frameworks. My zeal for problem solving and creativity motivates me to always learn new technologies and enhance my coding skills.

I'm delighted to contribute my passion and technical skills to a company that encourages development and creativity.

Education and IT Training

06/2024-Present Just IT Training Ltd, London

Digital Skills Bootcamp: Software Development

A twelve-week intensive bootcamp covering the fundamentals of

Web and Software development.

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL and Python.

03/2024 – 04/2024 Back2Work Group, Manchester

Digital Skills Bootcamp: Level 1 Certificate in Skills for Creative Industries, Level 2 Award in Website Design and Development and

Level 2 Award in Digital and IT Skills

A five-week intensive bootcamp covering the Digital and IT Skills, fundamentals of Web designing and development using Wix, Skills

for creative Industries.

Applications: Scratch, Wix, WordPress, Figma, Canva.

10/2006 - 09/2011 Nnamdi Azikiwe University Awka, Nigeria

Bachelor of Science in Radiography/Radiological Sciences

Grade: 2:1

09/1997-07/2003 Dennis Memorial Grammar School, Onitsha, Nigeria

West African Senior Secondary Certificate (WASSC)

A-C grades in subjects including Maths, English, Chemistry, Physics

and Biology.

IT Skills

Software Development Skills: Teamwork, Time-Management, Problem-solving, Attention to Details, Databases, Adaptability, Debugging, Coding and Software Testing.

Web Technology: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, GitHub and MySQL

Core Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python and SQL

Projects: Password Generator, Number Counter.

Employment History

12/2018 - Present Diana Princess of Wales Hospital Grimsby, UK Senior Radiographer

- Perform wide range of CT and MRI examinations in a very busy radiology department, by proactively and effectively prioritize tasks, and maintaining a high standard of patient care through careful planning and coordination.
- Responsible for coordinating imaging sessions for a diverse group of patients, including paediatric and geriatric patients.
- Manage daily patient appointment and schedule by prioritizing patients based on urgency, ensuring that critical cases received immediate attention while efficiently rescheduling nonurgent appointments.
- Provided compassionate and patient-centred care, ensuring a positive experience for all
 patients by addressing their concerns and explaining procedures clearly.
- Effectively communicated complex imaging results and procedural information to patients and healthcare team members, ensuring understanding and appropriate follow-up actions.
- Participated in regular team meetings, contributing ideas and feedback to improve departmental processes and patient care quality.

02/2013 - 11/2018 Pyramid Diagnostics Services, Portharcourt, Nigeria Rotational Radiographer

- Worked with diverse team of radiologists, nurses, and administrative staff to optimise imaging schedules, manage patient care, and perform various medical imaging examinations.
- Coordinated and prioritized patient appointments, balancing routine and emergency cases to maintain efficient workflow and minimize wait times.
- Efficiently managed a high volume of patient appointments, ensuring timely completion of imaging procedures and adherence to schedules.
- Quickly learned and implemented new imaging technologies and protocols, ensuring compliance with the latest healthcare standards and practices.

01/2012 - 01/2013 University of Ilorin Teaching Hospital, Ilorin, Nigeria Intern Radiographer

- Participate in team meetings, training sessions, and continuing education activities.
- Support senior radiographers in performing X-rays, CT scans, MRI scans, and other imaging procedures.
- Prepare and position patients for imaging, ensuring their comfort and safety during procedures
- Ensure accurate documentation of imaging procedures, including patient information and image quality reports.

01/2012 - 01/2013

System Plus Technologies and Cafe, Onitsha, Nigeria Customer Service Representative

- Delivered exceptional customer service by assisting clients with product selections, answering inquiries, and providing detailed product information.
- Effectively communicated with customers in-person and over the phone, providing clear and concise information about products, promotions, and store policies.
- Actively participated in team meetings and contributed ideas to improve store layout and customer experience.
- Addressed and resolved customer complaints and issues promptly, using problem-solving skills to ensure customer satisfaction and retention.

Interests and Achievements

Computing:

Hobbies: Swimming, Playing Lawn-Tennis, Travelling, Reading and Listening to Motivational books and audios.

Additional Info:

10/2011 AFRI Hub ICT In Partnership with Nnamdi Azikiwe University Awka,

Nigeria

Computer Skill Training: Certificate in Computer Fundamental

Packages: Microsoft Office, Page Maker, Coral Draw.

References available upon request